# KRISTEN STEELE

Software Developer

#### CONTACT

kristenraesteele@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/kristenraesteele github.com/krsteele krsteele.com

## **ABOUT**

Coming to tech from a Communications and Wellness background, I bring professionalism and a diverse skillset to software development. Having experience in design allows me to easily communicate about UI/UX and understand how to work with deadlines. I have the ability to take on new ideas and learn new concepts quickly, adapt easily to new situations, and relate to many types of people. I love that software development is a field that pushes me to stretch myself mentally and encourages continued personal growth.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML Python
CSS Django
JavaScript SQL
ReactJS Git
React-Bootstrap Github

MS Office Suite Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Adobe XD

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School | Full Stack Software Developer September 2020 - March 2021

A six-month intensive, full-time software development program focusing on project-based learning.

- Developed dynamic single-page web apps using ReactJs
- Built RESTful JSON APIs in Python with Django and SQLite
- Exposed to a simulated Agile environment
- Used Git and GitHub for version control
- Experience in fully remote collaboration

# **PROJECTS**

Daily Baby | Full Stack Capstone Project

Daily Baby helps parents of small children bridge the gap between the desire to keep a baby book and the actual daily reality of keeping one. Currently a full-CRUD journaling app, a new texting feature is currently being developed using Twilio. When complete, this app will text the user at their preferred time and frequency to remind them to record a journal entry, then store their response.

- Tech: ReactJS, Python with Django, React-Bootstrap, Cloudinary
- Client Repo: github.com/krsteele/daily-baby-client
- Server Repo: github.com/krsteele/daily-baby-server
- Demo Video: <a href="https://youtu.be/WU1eblpRUHw">https://youtu.be/WU1eblpRUHw</a>

Bespöke Hub | Client-Side Capstone Project

Bespōke Hub was built as a way for a friend, who restores and sells vintage boats, to keep track of the details of each boat, manage a project's progress, and seamlessly communicate that progress to his client via a dashboard.

- Tech: ReactJS, CSS, React-Bootstrap, Grommet, JSON-Server
- Repo: github.com/krsteele/bespoke-hub
- Demo Video: <a href="https://youtu.be/L0k\_OsCnEsl">https://youtu.be/L0k\_OsCnEsl</a>

Rare | Full Stack Group Project

A publishing platform and social app that allows authenticated users to create posts, associated tags, categories and comments. A full-CRUD app with a RESTful JSON API.

- Tech: ReactJS, CSS, HTML, Python, Django REST framework
- Client Repo: <a href="https://github.com/krsteele/rare-client-vicious-blizzards">https://github.com/krsteele/rare-client-vicious-blizzards</a>
- Server Repo: <a href="https://github.com/krsteele/rare-rest-api-rare-vicious-blizzards">https://github.com/krsteele/rare-rest-api-rare-vicious-blizzards</a>

#### PROJECTS CONTINUED

Nutshell | Client-Side Group Project

A CRUD social dashboard app with a task list, group chat, news, and events. Built as part of a four-person team, in a simulated Agile environment.

- Tech: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JSON-Server
- Repo: https://github.com/krsteele/nutshell-whiskered-gnomes
- Demo Video: https://youtu.be/vy5shqVO6YU

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Licensed Massage Therapist** | Independent Contractor September 2013 - October 2019

Therapeutic Massage Therapist licensed in the state of Tennessee

- Coordinated a schedule of personal clients, on-call work, and freelance events
- Managed business and tax records for my private practice
- Independent contractor for O.liv Body Bar, Revigorate Corporate Massage, Stage Hands Massage, and Back In Touch Wellness Center

**Santa Fe Opera** | Box Office Customer Service Representative June 2011 - August 2019

One of the world's premier summer opera festivals

• Telephone and in-person customer service and sales of opera tickets, season subscriptions, and other services using Tessitura Network software

**Westminster Presbyterian Church Nashville** | Communications Specialist June 2008 - February 2019

An active church with 2100+ members and a staff of 20+

- Started as administrative assistant in June 2008, promoted to communications assistant in October 2012, promoted to communications specialist in July 2017
- Increased member engagement as project manager for monthly magazine, website, bi-weekly newsletter, YouTube channel, and all social media accounts
- Coordinated volunteers and committees across multiple large-scale projects and special events

## **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School | Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp | September 2020 - March 2021

Cumberland Institute of Holistic Therapies | 500-hour Massage Therapy Certification

Nossi College of Art | Associate of Occupational Studies, Commercial Digital Photography

Pensacola State College | Associate of Arts, Liberal Studies